<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Machine learning | Lorenzo Dall&#39;Amico</title>
    <link>/tag/machine-learning/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Machine learning</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Machine learning</title>
      <link>/tag/machine-learning/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Study of f2f interactions</title>
      <link>/project/sociopatterns/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/sociopatterns/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Face-to-face proximity interactions are the main driver of different types of contagion such as epidemic, social and opinion opinion contagion. The 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sociopatterns.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Sociopatterns&lt;/a&gt; collaboration developed proximity sensors that are capable to measure contact patterns with a high resolution in both time and space. We deployed these sensors in schools, hospital and offices, but the focus has also been towards sub-Saharan African countries such as Kenya, Malawi and South-Africa that have to tolerate the highest epidemic burdens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scope of this project is to study the proximity measurements to understand better how humans interact (especially in low-resources countries) and being able to devise efficient epidemic mitigation polices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;related-works&#34;&gt;Related works&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;/publication/collectable/&#34;&gt;Estimating household contact matrices structure from easily collectable metadata&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spectral methods for graph clustering</title>
      <link>/project/sc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/sc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Network theory is of central importance in interdisciplinary science. The ability of recovering properties of items starting from their interaction has key applications in many fields, ranging from biology, to social science, passing through electronics and Physics. Clustering is the ability to group the items of a system in categories sharing similar properties. The spectral techinques represent a fast solution to this problem. Solving this problem for sparse and heterogenous networks is of utmost importance to address the problem on real graphs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;related-works&#34;&gt;Related works&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the following links you may find papers, slides, videos and codes related to my work in this project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://lorenzodallamico.github.io/publication/phd/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Spectral methods for graph clustering&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://lorenzodallamico.github.io/publication/bhnishimori/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Nishimori meets Bethe: a spectral method for node classification in sparse weighted graphs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://lorenzodallamico.github.io/publication/dbh20/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Community detection in sparse time-evolving graphs with a dynamical Bethe-Hessian&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://lorenzodallamico.github.io/publication/reg20/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Optimal Laplacian regularization for sparse spectral community detection&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://lorenzodallamico.github.io/publication/unified20/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;A unified framework for spectral clustering in sparse graphs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://lorenzodallamico.github.io/publication/bh19/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Revisiting the Bethe-Hessian: Improved Community Detection in Sparse Heterogeneous Graphs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://lorenzodallamico.github.io/publication/bhfirst/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Community detection in sparse realistic graphs: improving the Bethe-Hessian&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://lorenzodallamico.github.io/articles/gretsi19.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Classification spectrale par la laplacienne déformée dans des graphes réalistes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
